A Guide to the Papers of Paul T. David
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Paul T. David 1930-1941
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12793-a
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given as a gift to the University of Virginia Library on February 13, 1991.
Contents List
- Advisory Committee on Education Secretarial Files, 1930-1941
  - Abstracts and Reviews of Studies [1930-1940] (Box 1)
  - Biographical Data on Members [1938] (Box 1)
  - Budget Papers 1938-[1939] (Box 1)
  - Budget Papers [1937-1938], 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Chronological File--Major Correspondence [1936]-1938, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Chronological File--Major Correspondence 1939-1941, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Civilian Conservation Corps--Material for A[dvisory]; C[ommittee] on E[ducation] Report [1933-1938] (Box 2)
  - Cocking-Crawford Study on Control [1938] (Box 2)
  - Educational Policies Commission Chicago Conference 1937 Sept (Box 2)
  - History of Committee--Draft Committee [1936-1938] (Box 2)
  - --Working Papers [1936-1939], 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Kotschnig Correspondence [1937-1939] (Box 2)
  - Meetings of Committee--1st Meeting re Draft Minutes [1936] (Box 2)
  - --1st Meeting re Working Papers [1936] (Box 3)
  - --2nd Meeting re Draft Minutes [1936] (Box 3)
  - --2nd Meeting re Transcript [1936] (Box 3)
  - --2nd Meeting re Working Papers [n.d.] (Box 3)
  - --3rd Meeting re Draft Minutes [1937] (Box 3)
  - --3rd Meeting re Transcript [1937] (Box 3)
  - --3rd Meeting re Working Papers [1937] (Box 3)
  - --6th Meeting re Notes 1937 Nov 10-11 (Box 3)
  - --7th Meeting re Notes 1937 Nov 23-24 (Box 3)
  - Meetings of Committee--8th Meeting--Transcript 1937 Dec 9-11 (Box 3)
  - Meetings of Conference Committee--Draft Minutes [1936] (Box 3)
  - --Working Papers [1936] (Box 3)
  - Meetings of Executive Committee--6th Meeting--Transcript 1937 Dec 21 (Box 3)
  - --7th Meeting--Notes 1937 Dec 23 (Box 3)
  - --Current Working Papers [1938] (Box 3)
  - Memoranda to Committee--Press Comment on Report [1938] (Box 3)
  - Memoranda to Committee Members [1938-1939] (Box 3)
  - Memorandum for President--Working Papers, etc. [1938-1940] (Box 4)
  - Memoranda to Staff--Miscellaneous [1936-1938] (Box 4)
  - --General Instructions Memo No. 1 [1937] (Box 4)
  - --General Instructions Memo No. 2 [1937] (Box 4)
  - Message to Congress (Proposed) Working Materials [1938] (Box 4)
  - Occupational Outlook Service [1936-1937] (Box 4)
  - Pamphlet The Fed[eral] Gov[ernmen]t and Ed[ucation] Working Papers [1938] (Box 4)
  - Planning for Committee--Enlarged Study 1937 Apr-May (Box 4)
  - --General Principles Statement 1937 Jan (Box 4)
  - --Major Issues 1937 Summer, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Advisory Committee on Education--Report of the Committee [1938], 2 folders (Box 5)
  - --Business Meeting [1938] (Box 5)
  - Advisory Committee on Education-Minutes [1938 Jan 24] (Box 5)
  - --Minutes [1938 Jan 23] (Box 5)
  - --Minutes [1938 Jan 23] (Box 6)
  - --Minutes [1938 Jan 22] (Box 6)
  - --Minutes [1938 Jan 22] (Box 6)
  - --Minutes [1938 Jan 21] (Box 6)
  - --Transcript Book 1938 Jan 21 (Box 6)
  - Outline of Committee Meeting [1938] Jan 21 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Letters and Information [1938, n.d.], 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Meeting of Executive Committee--Minutes 1937 Sept 16 (Box 6)
  - Advisory Committee Meeting--Minutes 1937 Apr 23 (Box 6)
  - Notes on Business Meeting--8th Meeting of Committee 1937 Dec 9-11 (Box 6)
  - Transcript of Committee Meeting 1937 Dec 9-11 (Box 7)
  - Staff Meeting 1937 Nov 6 (Box 7)
  - Minutes--Executive Committee Meeting 1937 Dec 21, 23 (Box 7)
  - Notes on Committee Meeting with Staff 1937 Nov 10 (Box 7)
  - Notes on Committee Meeting 1937 Nov 23 (Box 7)
  - Annual Report Digest 1937-1938 (Box 7)
  - President's Committee on Vocational Education--Statements Submitted by Certain Organizations and Individuals--Part I [1937] (Box 7)
  - Draft No. 3--Partial Draft of a Report [1938], (1 of 2) (Box 7)
  - Draft No. 3--Partial Draft of a Report [1938], (2 of 2) (Box 8)
  - Draft Report of Committee [1938], 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Volume 2 of Draft 4 [1938], 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Office Diary [1936] (Box 8)
  - Personnel Sheets [1937-1938], (1 of 2) (Box 8)
  - Personnel Sheets [1937-1938], (2 of 2) (Box 9)
  - Statement of Policies for the Administration of Vocational Education [1936] (Box 9)
  - Congressional Record--Seventy Fifth 1937 May 20 (Box 9)
  - Planning for Committee--Study Plans [1936] (Box 9)
  - -- Voc[ational] Ed[ucation] Report Plans 1937 Apr (Box 9)
  - Planning Technicians' Conference--National Resources Committee [1938] (Box 9)
  - Press Releases [1938-1939], 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Professional Staff List 1937 Nov 9 (Box 9)
  - Publication of Materials by Staff Members, Policy, etc. [1938] (Box 9)
  - Quoddy Village NYA [National Youth Administration] Project--Emerson's Report, etc. [1937] (Box 10)
  - Recreation, Memoranda on Secretarial Files [1937] (Box 10)
  - Reid Authorship Case, Correspondence, etc. [1937-1939] (Box 10)
  - Requests for Information--Federal Agencies 1937 Feb (Box 10)
  - Schedules and Questionnaires [1937] (Box 10)
  - --President's Committee on Vocational Education Series [1937], 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Special File [1936-1938] (Box 10)
  - Staff Assignments [1937] (Box 10)
  - Staff Conferences [1937] (Box 10)
  - Staff Studies Schedules, Planning, etc [1938-1939] (Box 10)
  - Statement Approved by Committee 1937 Apr 24 (Box 10)
  - Vocational Education--Federal Board-Houle's Memo, etc. [1935-1937] (Box 11)
  - --Memo of Evaluation by Cocking [1937] (Box 11)
  - --Allotments--Correspondence, etc. 1937 (Box 11)
  - Voc[ational] Ed[ucation] Appropriations Material for Sen[ator] Hayden 1937 (Box 11)
  - Zinc Draft for C[hamber] of C[ommerce] Mtg [meeting] [1937] (Box 11)
  - The Federal Government and Education Published Booklet by Adv[isory] Comm[ittee] on Ed[ucation][1938] (Box 11)
  - Office Diary [1936-1938] (Box 11)
  - Minutes of the First Meeting [1936], 2 folders (Box 11)
  - File Copy of Meeting 1936 Nov 7, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Reading File--February 1937 Feb, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Reading File 1937 Jan (Box 12)
  - Outline for Discussion 1937 Nov, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Draft Outline 1937 Nov 15, 17, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Outline for Discussion 1937 Nov 21 (Box 12)
  - Selected Sections of a Report 1937 Dec 8 (Box 12)
  - Preliminary Draft No. 3 1938 Jan 17, (1 of 2) (Box 12)
  - Preliminary Draft No. 3 1938 Jan 17, (1 of 2) (Box 13)
  - Draft Report of the Committee [1938], 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Copy of the Report of Advisory Committee on Education [1938], 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Note to Miss Greenwald from P. T. David 1938 Oct 11 (Box 13)
  - Abstract of Transcript-Conference at Nashville, Tennessee [1937] (Box 13)
  - --Conference at New Orleans, Louisiana 1937 (Box 14)
  - --Conference at Chicago, Illinois 1937 (Box 14)
  - --Conference at Washington, D. C. 1937 (Box 14)
  - --Conference at New York 1937 (Box 14)
  - Statements Filed with the Committee by Federal Agencies 1937 (Box 14)
  - Statements Submitted by Certain Organizations and Individuals 1937 (Box 14)
  - Current Issues in Vocational Education 1937 Mar 13 (Box 14)
  - --Preliminary and Confidential--Not for Reference [1937] (Box 14)
  - Views and Recommendations on Questions Relating to Vocational Education--by Dr. John W. Studebaker [1937] (Box 14)
  - Annual Reports of State Boards for Vocational Education [1938] (Box 14)
  - Reading File 1937 Mar (Box 14)
  - Reading File 1937 Mar-Aug, 7 folders (Box 15)
  - Reading File 1837 Aug-Dec, 7 folders (Box 16)
  - Reading File 1938 Jan-Jul, 7 folders (Box 17)
  - Reading File 1938 Aug-1939 Apr, 9 folders (Box 18)
  - Reading File 1939 May-Jul, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - --Calvert School Correspondence Courses Memo by Mock 1939 Jun 9 (Box 19)
  - --Wagner-Davis Kindergarten Amendment 1939 May 16 (Box 19)
  - --Harrison-Thomas Bill and Report Parts 1, 2 and 3 1939 Apr 3 (Box 19)
  - --Hearings--Senate 1939 (Box 19)
  - --Senate Hearings--Statement prepared by Mr. Reeves 1939 Mar 2 (Box 19)
  - --Statistical Facts Pertinent to etc. by N[ational] E[ducation] A[ssociation] for Hearings 1939 Feb (Box 19)
  - --Harrison-Thomas Bill 1939 Feb 13 (Box 19)
  - --Larrabee Bill 1939 Jan 31 (Box 19)
  - --Memo for Harrison, Thomas and Larrabee 1939 Jan 27 (Box 19)
  - --House Education Committee Membership Material 1939 Jan (Box 19)
  - Federal Aid Legislation 1941 (Box 19)
  - --Statistical Materials for Hearings Prepared by F. Ramsey [1936-1939] (Box 20)
  - --Material for Speeches etc.--Current [1938-1939] (Box 20)
  - --Material for Hearings, etc. [1936-1940] (Box 20)
  - --Drafts and Working Papers 1939 Jan (Box 20)
  - --Drafts 1938 Dec (Box 20)
  - Federal Aid Legislation- N[ational] E[ducation] A[ssociation] Draft 1938 Oct 28 (Box 21)
  - --Memo by David on N[ational] E[ducation] A[ssociation] draft 1938 Oct 1 (Box 21)
  - N[ational] E[ducation] A[ssociation] Draft 1938 Oct 1 (Box 21)
  - --Address by President, Athens, Georgia 1938 Aug 11 (Box 21)
  - --Address of Harry Hopkins 1938 Aug 5 (Box 21)
  - --Conference 1938 Jul 25 (Box 21)
  - --Draft by Dawson of N[ational] E[ducation] A[ssociation]1938 Jul (Box 21)
  - --Address by President to N[ational] E[ducation] A[ssociation]1938 Jun 30 (Box 21)
  - --Conference 1938 May 11 (Box 21)
  - --Memorandum Explaining Bill--By P. T. David 1938 May 6 (Box 21)
  - --Miscellaneous Papers 1938 Apr-Dec (Box 21)
  - --Fletcher Bill 1938 Apr 21 (Box 21)
  - --Comments by R. R. Hamilton on Draft Bill 1938 Apr (Box 21)
  - --Harrison-Thomas Amendment 1938 Apr (Box 21)
  - --Conference 1938 Mar 23 (Box 21)
  - --Draft Bills (Dawson, David etc.) 1938 Mar, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - --Address by Mr. Reeves to N[ational] E[ducation] A[ssociation]1938 Feb 28 (Box 21)
  - --Summary of Report of the Committee (Press Release) 1938 Feb 23 (Box 21)
  - --Analysis of Hearings on Harrison Black-Fletcher Bill 1937 (Box 21)
  - Federal Aid Legislation-Hearings-Senate and House 1937, 2 folders (Box 22)
  - --Fletcher Bill 1937 Jan-Mar (Box 22)
  - --Harrison-Black Bill and Senate Committee Report 1937 Jan, Mar (Box 22)
  - Legislation-Proposed Federal Memo Indexing Bills as of April 30 1939 Apr 30 (Box 22)
  - --Proposed Federal Analysis Status 1938 Apr (Box 22)
  - Youth Legislation-Proposed National Youth Service Act of 1938 and Working Papers 1938 (Box 22)
  - Vocational Education Legislation [V. E. L.]--Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 Material 1938 (Box 22)
  - --Material for Hearings [1939] (Box 22)
  - --Probable Effects of George-Larrabee Bill--Memo for Miss Thorne 1939 Jun 24 (Box 22)
  - --George Bill, S. 2460 1939 May 19 (Box 22)
  - --Larrabee Bill, H. R. 6157 1939 May 4 (Box 22)
  - --Draft Statement on Proposed Bill 1939 Apr 27 (Box 22)
  - --Materials for Mr. Reeves for AFL Conference 1939 Apr 20 (Box 22)
  - AFL Draft Bill 1939 Apr 20 (Box 22)
  - --Draft Bill and Memorandum 1939 Jan (Box 22)
  - --Memoranda on Voc[ational] Ed[ucation] Section Draft Federal Aid Bill 1938 Mar (Box 22)
  - --Needs of Voc[ational] Rehab[ilitation] Service in U. S. [1938] (Box 22)
  - Harrison-Thomas Bill--77th Congress 1941 Apr 7 (Box 22)
  - Office Diary--Loose Papers [1936-1940] (Box 22)